Contact

rodriguez_angel93@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ angelrodriguezmph (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Infectious Diseases
Data Science
Epidemiology

Languages

Spanish (Full Professional)

Certifications

Introduction to incident Command System ICS-100

COVID-19 Contact Tracing

An introduction to the National Incident Management System

Basic Incident Command System for Initial Response

Angel Rodriguez

Epidemiologist at Ector County Health Department

El Paso Metropolitan Area

Summary

MS student for Data Science, Masters in Public Health with a concentration in epidemiology, having thirteen years of experience in public health from dental offices to the Department of Public Health. Immense experience in infectious disease prevention and analysis.

Experience

Ector County Health Department Epidemiologist

May 2021 - September 2021 (5 months)

- •Plan and direct studies of public health problems to find ways to prevent and treat them if they arise
- •Collect and analyze data—through observations, interviews, and surveys, data entry for new cases, vaccination, and investigations
- •Communicate their findings to health practitioners, policymakers, and the public
- •Manage public health programs by planning programs, monitoring their progress, analyzing data, and seeking ways to improve the programs in order to improve public health outcomes
- •Supervise professional, technical, and clerical personnel

MIDLAND COUNTY HEALTH DEPARTMENT

Epidemiologist

September 2020 - May 2021 (9 months)

- •Plan and direct studies of public health problems to find ways to prevent and treat them if they arise
- •Collect and analyze data—through observations, interviews, and surveys, data entry for new cases, vaccination, and investigations
- •Communicate their findings to health practitioners, policymakers, and the public
- •Manage public health programs by planning programs, monitoring their progress, analyzing data, and seeking ways to improve the programs in order to improve public health outcomes

•Supervise professional, technical, and clerical personnel

COVID-19 Site Manager May 2020 - August 2020 (4 months)

El Paso, Texas, United States

Assisted with emergency health responses to disease outbreaks.

- Review activity reports, or other performance data to measure productivity or goal achievement or to identify areas program improvement.
- Perform personnel functions such as selection, training, or evaluation.
- Establish or implement departmental policies, goals, objectives, or procedures in conjunction with board members, organization officials, or staff members.
- Plan or direct activities such as coordination with other department managers.
- Implement or oversee environmental management or sustainability programs addressing issues such as

Bio-hazard disposals, conservation, or waste management.

• Developed organization and flow according to Infection control guidelines

New Mexico Department of Health WIC Nutritionist January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months) Carlsbad, New Mexico, United States

- Provides initial WIC assessment for WIC client and develops nutrition care plans with client-centered goals and monitor client's progress towards those goals
- Coordinate client services and referrals with appropriate agencies.
- Participate in case plan reviews and interdisciplinary team meetings.
- Provides initial counseling to all high-risk participants.
- Participate in completing and evaluating departmental policies and procedures.
- Participate in periodic review of records to evaluate compliance and standard of care.

Doniphan Family Dental Lead Dental Assistant August 2010 - January 2020 (9 years 6 months) Canutillo, Texas, United States

- Management of occupational exposures to bloodborne pathogens, including postexposure prophylaxis (PEP) for work exposures to hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV); and human immunodeficiency virus(HIV).
- Selection and use of devices with features designed to prevent sharps injury.
- Dental water-quality concerns (e.g., dental unit waterline biofilms; delivery of water of acceptable biological quality for patient care; usefulness of flushing waterlines

Dona Ana Detention Center (CORIZON)
Infection Prevention Dental Assistant
June 2014 - May 2015 (1 year)

Dona Ana County, New Mexico, United States

- Management of occupational exposures to bloodborne pathogens, including postexposure prophylaxis (PEP) for work exposures to hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV); and human immunodeficiency virus(HIV).
- Selection and use of devices with features designed to prevent sharps injury.
- Dental water-quality concerns (e.g., dental unit waterline biofilms; delivery of water of acceptable biological quality for patient care; usefulness of flushing water lines

Education

Eastern University

Master's degree, Data Science · (August 2021 - August 2022)

Purdue University

Master of Public Health - MPH · (2017 - 2019)

The University of Texas at El Paso

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biology/Biological Sciences, General · (2014 - 2016)